Guide to the Gay Cable Network Archives, 1982-2001 MSS.231
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series X: Gay USA, 154212
  - 1994 Vol. XII, 246294
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 36 [Air date: 9/8/1994], September 1994; ID: 231.0418; 155270 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0418)
      6. Lavender Health: Coverage of the 12th Annual American Association of Physicians for Human Rights conference. Jane Petro and Bob Cabaj of AAPHR, and a medical student named Clarissa Kripke are interviewed. Kate O'Hanlan speaks.
      7. Damien Corboy is interviewed about the House of Representatives.
      8. The Lambda Update: Gay and lesbian adoption is covered. Beatrice Dohrn is interviewed.
      9. Wigstock 94 is covered.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 37 [Air date: 9/15/1994], September 1994; ID: 231.0419; 155284 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0419)
      1. GCN's Coverage of the 1994 Primaries. Lee Sharmat and Damien Corby report. Mario Cuomo speaks and is interviewed about the gay and lesbian civil rights bill. The Attorney General race is covered from Karen Burstein's HQ. Burstein makes a speech. Catherine Aboti, newly elected state senator, is interviewed. Tom Duane speaks after losing his congressional run. Chris Quinn, campaign manager, political analyst Bob Bailey, and Jerry Nadler are interviewed.
      2. News Notes: 60 Minutes interviews Bob McFarlane, former advisor to Reagan, who calls Oliver North a 'degenerate liar'. Shannon Faulkner, student at The Citadel, is covered. African-American women 15 times more likely to have AIDS than white women. Gay students are being assaulted in Washington state schools and few reports have been filed because the abuse is so routine for gay and lesbian students. Forced HIV testing being considered in Russia. OJ Simpson gossip. OutLoud is announced. California governor Pete Wilson vetoes domestic partners law. Humm and Sharmat discuss Priscilla: Queen of the Desert.
      3. Gabriel Rotello interviewed about his controversial Newsday piece about AIDS and the gay community. In a follow-up, Michelangelo Signorelli discusses his column in Out Magazine with a similar theme.
      5. GLAAD Media Alert: Parade, a very mainstream family-oriented Sunday news magazine, covers gay and lesbian parents, and interviews kids with gay and lesbian parents. Viewers are encouraged to write to Parade, which Parade actively encourages.
      COMMERCIAL: Black and Blue Ball in Montreal, Tour Du Jour.
      6. Lavender Health: Further coverage of the 12th Annual American Association of Physicians for Human Rights conference. Walt Odets, a clinical psychologist, speaks. Marj Plumb, lesbian health policy advocate also speaks.
      COMMERCIAL: Urad Leather Cream ("You can treat me bad… but you gotta treat your leather right.")
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 38 [Air date: 9/22/1994], September 1994; ID: 231.0420; 155285 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0420)
      1. News Notes: Michael Feinstein comes out of the closet, complete with cover interview on The Advocate. AIDS fundraiser at the Playboy mansion. More organizations pulling events out of Cobb County in Georgia. Division of AIDS Services is saved in New York. Richard Dreyfuss directing version of Hamlet with a lesbian Ophelia and Gertrude, leading to one actress leaving the play. Woman who was fired from Dallas police force for being a lesbian wins lawsuit against city, leading to hiring policy changes. Gay and lesbian themed films and TV are discussed, including the film version of Jeffery and Harvey Firestein's sitcom on CBS. GLAAD goes national.
      2. Analysis of the primaries. Lee Sharmat, Andy Humm, Damien Corby, and David Blanton discuss the primaries.
      3. The Lambda Update: Denny Lee introduces this segment on Lambda's work on the Non-Discrimination Act. Evan Wolfson is interviewed.
      4. GLAAD Media Alert: Gay characters on Melrose Place causing headaches at Fox, with episodes being toned down due to 'economics'; My So-Called Life on ABC features a recurring bisexual character. The Brady Bunch Movie may feature a lesbian character. Viewers are encouraged to write to Paramount Pictures.
      5. Lavender Health: 12th Annual American Association of Physicians for Human Rights conference. Safe sex for lesbians. Amber Hollibaugh, Laura Ramos, Rochelle Burroughs, and Ana L. Oliveira speak.
      COMMERCIAL: Poz Magazine
      6. Stonewall exhibit at the NYPL. Lou Maletta reports on Becoming Visible: The Legacy of Stonewall. (this is a re-airing of an earlier segment)
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 39 [Air date: 9/29/1994], September 1994; ID: 231.0421; 155286 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0421)
      1. News Notes: First gay pride parade in Tokyo attracts mostly lesbians. Australia has eliminated all but one sodomy law. Mississippi high school cancels gay-themed play. Cuba has camps for people with HIV. The number for No on 13, a protest on anti-gay legislation in Oregon is displayed.
      2. Bob and Rod. Leonard Rosenblatt interviews Rod Jackson and Bob Paris, authors of Bob and Rod.
      COMMERCIAL: GMHC Presents Angels on Ice
      3. David Blanton interviews Gerardo Ramirez of the Log Cabin Club in New York, who is encouraging gays to vote Republican.
      4. GLAAD Media Alert: NBC Nightly News runs a series Gay in America. Viewers are encouraged to write to NBC. A few clips are shown.
      COMMERCIAL: AIDS Walk Long Island
      5. Lavender Health: Tuberculosis short PSA. Thomas Freeden of the New York City Bureau of Tuberculosis Control.
      6. Mr. Drummer 1994. Leather event in San Francisco.
      COMMERCIAL: Support Human Rights for Lesbian and Gay People.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 40 [Air date: 10/6/1994], October 1994; ID: 231.0422; 155287 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0422)
      1. News Notes: Gay-bashing in Wisconsin. Scandal in France over blood supplied to hemophiliacs in 1985; instead of getting an American blood testing kit, the French waited an entire year until a French company developed a blood testing kit. During this time approx. 1,200 people were infected with HIV. Rueben Diaz controversy continues. In Phoenix, a gay couple's home is vandalized, and it takes 8 hours for police to respond. Jay Severin says to feminists who are angry that Pataki is not pro choice: "Fuck those fucking lesbian communists. They don't get to define pro-choice." Damien Corby reports that 67% of those polled in Ireland support gay marriage.
      2. The Da Da Ball at Webster Hall. Garth Clark and Mark del Vecchio are interviewed. Tippi Hedren will introduce the event.
      3. Phone interview with Julie Davis of No on 13 in Oregon. Davis and others, including Oregon's governor, are trying to defeat anti-gay legislation.
      4. Carmen Vasquez from the Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center announces a voter registration drive.
      5. OutLoud Expo at Pier 92. Roz Winter, organizer, is interviewed.
      6. Ann Northrop is interviewed about the current state of gay rights organizations.
      7. GLAAD Media Alert: Snapple sponsors Rush Limbaugh's show, in spite of Snapple's anti-discrimination policies. Viewers are encouraged to write to Snapple and encourage them to pull their sponsorship.
      8. Lavender Health: Victoria H. Raveis is interviewed.
      9. The Lambda Update: Barry Taylor is interviewed about the Americans With Disabilities Act.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 41 [Air date: 10/13/1994], October 1994; ID: 231.0423; 155288 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0423)
      1. News Notes: Reporting from Coming Out Day at Christopher Street. Guy Molinari states Karen Burstein, Democratic nominee for Attorney General in New York, was not qualified for the job because she is an open lesbian. Helms' anti-gay bill is defeated. James Jennings in convicted. 40% of attempts to censor ciriculums in schools succeeded in the past year. Rueben Diaz gets a pitcher of water thrown at him.
      2. Lou Maletta reports from the Dada Ball. Some very elaborate costumes are showcased.
      3. Gay and Lesbian Business Expo '94, also known as Outloud. Linda Grishman, Mikel of the G Mikel Salon, James E. Law of IDS Financial Services, and Philip the editor of Uncommon Heroes.
      4. Black and Blue Ball in Montreal. Dale Hogan and Jay Henry report. Partygoers are interviewed.
      5. Empire State Pride Agenda annual gala. Dick Gottfreid, Alan Hevesi, Vivian Shapiro, Gabriel Rotello of Newsday, Francis Kunreuther, Karen Burstein, Mario Cuomo, and Mark Green are interviewed. Charles Millard refuses to be interviewed. Mario Cuomo gives a speech.
      6. Lavender Health: Gabriel A. Torres discusses cryptosporidium being found in New York City drinking water.
      7. GLAAD Media Alert: Guy Molinari's homophobic statements about Karen Burstein are covered. GLAAD is calling for Molinari's immediate dismissal.
      COMMERCIAL: Suave Succubus at the Wings Theater
      8. Guy Molinari's anti-gay comments are shown. The Anti-Violence Project is holding a protest; Ed Sedarbaum announces the logistics.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 42 [Air date: 10/20/1994], October 1994; ID: 231.0424; 155289 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0424)
      1. News Notes: Robert Kase shot in a gay crusing area. Viewers who have been harassed are encouraged to call the Anti-Violence Project. Cobb County opens its first gay disco. Two male octopi having sex is taped by scientists. HGH can help people with AIDS. Two gay men murdered in Mississippi. The Magic Binoculars by Carmine Red is mentioned.
      2. Lou Maletta interviews Brad Kimmelman and Salvatore Moltisanti of Zuma Records.
      3. Gay and Lesbian Anti-Violence Project goes to Long Island to protest Guy Molinari. H. Carl McCall is interviewed. It is revealed that Molinari is anti-abortion even though his wife recently had an abortion. Jimmy Breslin reports that a former Molinari aide has stated Molinari's anti-gay remarks were to get back at his gay brother.
      4. Lou Maletta and Joe Manto, a specialist in water treatment, discuss cryptosporidium.
      COMMERCIAL: Professional Plumbing, Specialists in Water Treatment Systems.
      5. GLAAD Media Alert: Visa supports the Gay Games, which causes Pat Robertson to call on his followers to cut up their cards in protest. Businesses in the Midwest are trying to get Visa cards pulled from stores. AT&T runs an ad in The Advocate, leading to protests from the right. Viewers are encouraged to write to Visa and AT&T to counter the right's homophobia.
      6. Lavender Health: Sexual assault is discussed. Bea Hanson of the Anti-Violence Project is interviewed.
      7. The Lambda Update: Amendment 2, which repealed gay rights in Colorado, is discussed. Suzanne B. Goldberg is interviewed.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 43 [Air date: 10/27/1994], October 1994; ID: 231.0425; 155290 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0425)
      1. News Notes: Jack Wrangler gets married. Charles Busch about to make stage debut as a man. Bob Grant radio show makes racist remarks. National Hemophilia Council facing lawsuits. Susan Molinari gets married to quash rumors that she is a lesbian. More evidence that Oliver North is gay. Andy Humm recommends Ed Wood.
      2. At the New York Hilton, protests during a Pataki fundraiser. Protesters are interviewed. Donna Minkowitz, Jeannine Hakin, Vinnie Maniscalco among those interviewed outside. Al D'Amato, Marcus Duran, John Dunne, Dov Hikind, Roy Goodman (who repeatedly denies Pataki is against the civil rights bill), and Andrew Eristroff interviewed during the fundraiser by Andy Humm.
      3. Karen Burstein fundraiser. Marjorie Hill and Burstein are interviewed. Deborah Glick, Karen Burstein, and Tom Duane speak.
      4. Figure skating is shown.
      5. Lavender Health: Assisted suicide is covered. Tracy Miller of Task Force on Life and the Law, Senator Franz Leichter, and Carla Kerr are interviewed.
      6. GLAAD Media Alert: The New York Times films a commercial with Rush Limbaugh endorsing them. Viewers are encouraged to write the Times and order they drop Limbaugh, withdraw the commercial, and publicly apologize.
      7. Lou Maletta interviews Tom Murdock about his new play, Key West. A clip from the play is shown. Cynthia Moss, an actress in the play, is also interviewed.
      COMMERCIAL: Heavenly Bodies, Circle Line Cruise Ship
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 44 [Air date: 11/3/1994], November 1994; ID: 231.0426; 155320 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0426)
      1. News Notes: Supreme Court refuses to hear case of gay man kicked out of army. ACT UP meeting goes badly amid declining membership and funding. New study reveals condom usage up among teens. Lily Tomlin comes out. The Republican party is overwhelmingly anti-gay. Oprah says gay men can't get to heaven. Unauthorized Marlon Brando biography alleges he was bisexual. Nancy Schaffer is assigned bodyguards after death threats.
      2. Local political round-up. Gay Men's Health Crisis reports on the candidates. Pataki refused to answer any polls conducted by GMHC. Herbert London is extremely homophobic. Karen Burstein's opponents accuse her of pedophilia.
      3. Damien Corboy interviewed about House and Senate races, which he says are in 'big trouble' of getting taken over by the Republicans. The Texas race with George Bush Jr. is discussed. Crown Prince of Denmark was seen walking out of gay book store.
      4. Lambda Update: Catherine Hanssens is interviewed.
      5. HomoXtra splits off part of their magazine into SX Magazine. Mark Berkley and Matthew Bank are interviewed.
      6. GLAAD Media Alert: Bob Grant of WABC makes homophobic and racist remarks, causing boycotts. Viewers are encouraged to write to WABC and demand Grant be dropped.
      7. Lavender Health: John Miller and Charles Kirtlew of Gay Circles are interviewed.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 45 [Air date: 11/10/1994], November 1994; ID: 231.0427; 155328 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0427)
      1. News Notes: Cancer drug being used for AIDS treatment. The BBC is making a Stonewall movie and the owner of the Stonewall bar is refusing to let them shoot there. Gay activists arrested and tortured in Albania. Anti-gay votes have cost over $180 million. Susan Smith and James R. Scott are covered. James Woods makes racist and homophobic remarks.
      2. Election Night. Tom Duane, Deborah Glick, and Dick Dadey interviewed in the wake of Pataki's win. Karen Burstein speaks.
      3. Andy Humm laments that the election results have put gay rights at a standstill.
      4. Amit Kama, of the Society for the Protection of Personal Rights in Israel is interviewed.
      5. Lavender Health: Marj Plumb, director of Lesbian Health at the Office of Gay and Lesbian Health is interviewed.
      6. GLAAD Media Alert: The New York Times article 'Gay and Black: A High-Wire Act' is praised. Viewers are encouraged to write The New York Times.
      7. Lou Maletta covers the production of Stonewall, a BBC film. A few of the cast and crew are interviewed including Christine Vachon, Guillermo Diaz, and Nigel Finch.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 46 [Air date: 11/17/1994], November 1994; ID: 231.0428; 155329 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0428)
      1. News Notes: Humm states Cardinal Ratzinger is the most rumored candidate to take over the position of Pope. Patsy Flemming is the new AIDS czar. Clips of Pedro Zamora on The Real World are shown, as is a speech on Zamora by Bill Clinton.
      2. Dick Dadey is interviewed about the aftermath of the '94 elections. A clip of Karen Burstein on NY1 is shown.
      3. Damien Corboy discusses the national results of the '94 election. Newt Gingrich is discussed, as is his lesbian sister.
      4. Lavender Health: Amber Hollibaugh is interviewed.
      5. GLAAD Media Alert: Donahue runs a 1-hour special on black homophobia including a black minister who stated he would rather march alongside the KKK than support gay rights. Viewers are encouraged to write to the executive producer of the Donahue show.
      COMMERCIAL: Lou Maletta Announces How to Advertise on GCN
      6. Lou Maletta interviews Ira Siff. A cliff is shown.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 47 [Air date: 11/24/1994], November 1994; ID: 231.0429; 155330 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0429)
      1. News Notes: Pennsylvania becomes the most Republican state. Serial killer of gay men is on the FBI's 10 most wanted. Jeremy Gerard of Variety makes homophobic statements. New York Daily News continuing to fight against woman who was raped in Prospect Park.
      2. Are We Surviving?: At the Gay and Lesbian Community Center. Gabriel Rotello of Newsday and Michelangelo Signorile interviewed.
      3. Jerry Nadler is interviewed about the election aftermath.
      4. Lou Maletta interviews Paulette Jacobson and Tony Ferrante, authors of Letters from the Closet.
      5. Lavender Health: Walt Odets and Marj Plumb speak at the American Association of Physicians for Human Rights Symposium.
      6. Lambda Update: Beatrice Dohrn discusses the Joe Steffan case.
      7. GLAAD Media Alert: Several gay and lesbian characters featured on network TV. Viewers are encouraged to write to the producers of Sisters.
      8. Marilyn Cooper of PFLAG is interviewed about an anti-gay travel company, Travel and Leisure.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 48 [Air date: 12/1/1994], December 1994; ID: 231.0430; 155331 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0430)
      1. News Notes: Ban on gays in the military upheld. Newt Gingrich mentioned. Crackdown on sexually oriented businesses in New York. Jesse Helms in trouble. Guy Molinari admits if he had not made anti-gay remarks, Karen Burstein would have been elected. Slide for Pride '95 announced.
      2. GMHC AIDS Danceathon: Rosie Perez, Salt n Pepa, and Queen Latifah perform.
      3. Ed Anderson reports on the victory party for Sheila James Kuehl, the first open lesbian in the California assembly. John Heilman, Sheila James Kuehl interviewed.
      4. The Lambda Update: Joseph Steffan case covered by Beatrice Dohrn. (repeat from 429)
      5. Jerry Nadler is interviewed about the election aftermath. (repeat from 429)
      COMMERCIAL: Coming Out Workshop Presented by PFLAG at the Lesbian and Gay Community Center
      6. Lavender Health: Frank Carbone of Body Positive is interviewed.
      COMMERCIAL: Urad Leather Cream featuring Lou Maletta
      7. Interview with Arthur Kirson. He performs at The Green Room.
      8. GLAAD Media Alert: The New York Times' election coverage is praised. Viewers are encouraged to write to the Times.
      9. GCN Seattle Washington: Deborah Glick, Kyle Rae, Patrick Hogan, Bob Gentry, Michael Spencer speak.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 49 [Air date: 12/8/1994], December 1994; ID: 231.0431; 155332 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0431)
      1. News Notes: National Lesbian and Gay Taskforce gets new director, Linda Paras. Anti-gay legislation continues. Rudy Giuliani gets a new nickname, 'Rudolph the Redneck Mayor' due to gutting of AIDS services. Newt Gingrich is asked on "Meet the Press" if he supports gays.
      2. Unveiling of the 'Red Ribbons Are Nice' campaign on World AIDS Day. Kenneth Cole is interviedwed. Lou Maletta reports from the Body Shop and interviews Bill Exeros. At the Metropolitan Museum of Art, Fred Davey gives a speech on Day Without Art. Dale Hogan reports from inside the Met. The NYPLPA is also shown, as is the Latino Community Names Project. Charles King is interviewed. Candlelight Vigil with speech by Brent Nicholson-Earl. The vigil march is shown.
      3. The passing of Elizabeth Glaser and Andy Kopkind covered.
      4. Andy Garcia taking on role of gay poet in Spanish Civil War. Filmmakers Brian Sloan, director of Pool Days and Raoul O'Connor, director of Friend of Dorothy are interviewed. Clips from these films and The Disco Years are shown.
      5. Lavender Health: Ravinia Hayes-Cozier is interviewed.
      6. GLAAD Media Alert: Jerry Springer show viciously attacks transsexual adolescent. Viewers are encouraged to write the show.
      7. GCN Special Report: Pataki tries to rescind health benefits for gays and lesbians.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 50 [Air date: 12/15/1994], December 1994; ID: 231.0432; 155333 (Box 27, Media ID: 231.0432)
      1. News Notes: Linda Paras is questioned for her management problems. George Pataki trying to get rid of domestic partnership benefits. Jesse Helms knocks ornaments of cherubs off a Christmas tree, referring to them as 'child pornography'. Dolly Parton says she would have been 'a drag queen' had she been born a man.
      2. Dick Dadey interviewed about George Pataki and the Pride Agenda meeting in Albany.
      3. 25th anniversary of the Gay Activists Alliance. Rich Wandel, Lew Todd, Allen Roskoff, Mark Rubin, Pete Fisher, Charles Silverstein, Michael Lavery, Don Teal, Joe Kennedy, Rose Jordan, Ron Gold, Randy Wicker, and John Paul Hudson interviewed.
      4. Mark Blasius, author of Lesbian and Gay Politics, is interviewed.
      5. Lou Maletta interviews Martha Wash, the singer for "It's Raining Men", about a large-size clothing line she's launching.
      6. Lavender Health: Part 2 of interview with Ravinia Hayes-Cozier.
      7. The Lambda Update: Suzanne Goldberg discusses anti-gay initiatives post-election. 8. GLAAD Media Alert: The Wall Street Journal runs article on Republicans backing down from anti-gay biases. Viewers are encouraged to write to Robert Bartley of the Journal.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 51 [Air date: 12/22/1994], December 1994; ID: 231.0433; 155334 (Box 28, Media ID: 231.0433)
      1. News Notes: Republicans trying to defund PBS. The Advocate runs into trouble over a bonus. ABC drops My So-Called Life. In Ireland, reverend Lee Cosgrove dies of a heart attack at a gay sauna and is given last rites by two priests who just happened to be there. Maya Angelou has cancelled several college visits because of a run-in with Fred Phelps.
      2. Brad Williams interviews Aduato Belarmino Alves.
      3. Happy Holidays bumper.
      4. Happy Holidays bumper 2.
      5. Bob Kingdom of The Truman Capote Talk Show is interviewed. A few clips are shown.
      6. Happy Holidays bumper 3.
      7. Happy Holidays bumper 4.
      8. AIDS News: Vaccine trials begin outside the US.
      9. Happy Holidays bumper 5.
      10. Happy Holidays bumper 6.
      11. Lavender Health: An excerpt from Having Fun Never Has to End is shown, as well as interview with Arbert Santana of GMHC and House of Latex.
      12. Happy Holidays bumper 7.
      13. GLAAD Media Alerts: Victor/Victoria is brought to Broadway. One song featured homophobic lyrics. GLAAD informed Blake Edwards, who reworked the song and removed the offending lyrics.
      14. Happy Holidays bumper 8.
      15. Happy Holidays bumper 9.
      16. DIFFA celebrates 10th Anniversary. Angela Cummings and Rosemary Kuropat interviewed.
      17. Happy Holidays bumper 10.
      COMMERCIAL: KISS 142 West 10th Street.
      18. Happy Holidays bumper 11.
    - Gay USA, Vol. XII, Episode No. 52 [Air date: 12/29/1994], December 1994; ID: 231.0434; 155335 (Box 28, Media ID: 231.0434)
      Program content: Year in Review
      COMMERCIAL: Kiss, West 10th Street
      1. News Notes: Year in Review. Giuliani shuts out the gay community. Dali Lama comes out in favor of gay relationships. ACT UP protests Giuliani's first day (archive footage).
      2. William Hall appointed to head up AIDS research. Rueben Diaz' homophobic remarks. The Pope says gay families 'not real families'. Tom Hanks' Oscar speech for Philadelphia shown. Gay Mexican man granted political asylum in the US. Boston St. Patrick's Day Parade cancelled when organizers are told they have to include gay groups. The New York St. Patrick's Day Parade is shown. Interview with Billy Jean King shown. Interview by Andy Humm with George Pataki shown.